<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-20T18:21:11-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Clinical Informatics Primer</title><subtitle>Harsh, Regina, Kathleen, Hannah</subtitle><author><name>Team Phoenix</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/04/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2019-04-20T16:58:32-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-20T16:58:32-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/04/20/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/04/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Team Phoenix</name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on healthcare access and class outlook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-harsh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on healthcare access and class outlook" /><published>2019-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-harsh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-harsh.html">&lt;p&gt;Coming into the class, I do not have much first hand experience with the “cogs” of the current United States healthcare ecosystem and the history that shaped and continues to shape its evolution. I know of some of the players that were involved, such as patients, providers, insurance companies, EHR vendors, hospitals, labs, researchers, and the government, but I would like to better understand how the different workflows interact and how information is exchanged. By knowing this, I think I will be better able to provide input on how and what changes should be considered to better the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind and in order to begin digging deeper into such a complex mess of interactions, I selected reading about “Healthcare Access”, chapters 3 and 13 of the “Understanding Health Policy: A Clinical Approach” textbook by Bodenheimer and Grumbach. The book itself was pretty well written, with examples from hypothetical patients interspersed with statistics and findings from recent studies and legislation. The text was easy to read and the figures provided added color to the commentary. I may, if time permits, read the other chapters that my team members were assigned simply because the book is a good resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the concept of writing a primer for the next class of biomedical informaticians very interesting. I think it will both help summarize the topics discussed in class for me and train me in writing complex issues in a way that is easy for others to understand, a very useful skill in my opinion. The lack of a strict rubric and structure is also nice because it allows us to be a bit creative in how we create this primer. This could lead to some challenges in the future, but so far, we have not run into any major hiccups. We decided to go with a blog-style primer, hosted on a Github Pages repository so that everyone can contribute easily and we can track the changes made. We did decide to use an existing free-for-use HTML and CSS template (with credit given to the creators of course), and I think this was a nice balance between using a web hosting site like Weebly or WordPress and creating a new website from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing how our primer will evolve in the future. We have some ideas about doing videos and podcasts for some of the chapters, and I think they will be a great break from the text descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harsh</name></author><summary type="html">Coming into the class, I do not have much first hand experience with the “cogs” of the current United States healthcare ecosystem and the history that shaped and continues to shape its evolution. I know of some of the players that were involved, such as patients, providers, insurance companies, EHR vendors, hospitals, labs, researchers, and the government, but I would like to better understand how the different workflows interact and how information is exchanged. By knowing this, I think I will be better able to provide input on how and what changes should be considered to better the system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unexpectedly complicated</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-regina.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unexpectedly complicated" /><published>2019-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-regina</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reactions/2019/04/20/reaction-regina.html">&lt;p&gt;Understanding how the US Healthcare system works has been more complicated of what I expected. The fact that many players are involved and that all of them have a hard time improving the provided healthcare made me think how feasible it is to change the US healthcare system. Coming from a middle-income country, I thought that the system would work flawlessly and that the patient will have always the best quality care but reading the chapters related to the quality of care that patients are receiving reminds me of all the disparities I saw back home where only the rich and famous were guarantee of getting the best doctors with the best treatments and medications. I don’t believe any country has a ‘perfect healthcare system’ because we can always improve but I think that for improving we need to start having a public health perspective where prevention is key and we need to stop seeing healthcare only as a revenue where people are making profits out of other people sickness and ill-being. This means not only thinking healthcare for the individual patient but seeing a whole community as the patient.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina</name></author><summary type="html">Understanding how the US Healthcare system works has been more complicated of what I expected. The fact that many players are involved and that all of them have a hard time improving the provided healthcare made me think how feasible it is to change the US healthcare system. Coming from a middle-income country, I thought that the system would work flawlessly and that the patient will have always the best quality care but reading the chapters related to the quality of care that patients are receiving reminds me of all the disparities I saw back home where only the rich and famous were guarantee of getting the best doctors with the best treatments and medications. I don’t believe any country has a ‘perfect healthcare system’ because we can always improve but I think that for improving we need to start having a public health perspective where prevention is key and we need to stop seeing healthcare only as a revenue where people are making profits out of other people sickness and ill-being. This means not only thinking healthcare for the individual patient but seeing a whole community as the patient.</summary></entry></feed>